Dharmendra Dhar Dubey, learned Amicus Curiae do not stand against the punishment awarded to the accused by the court below, since the court below has thoroughly discussed each and every aspect of the case and has rightly arrived at conclusion about the guilt of the appellant.
The Family Court below dismissed the suit, stating that since the property belonged to the mother-in-law, it is not the subject matter between the husband and wife and accordingly, the suit was not maintainable.
Since all these four appeals arising out of a common judgment passed by the Court below, these matters were clubbed with each other and a common argument was heard from both side.
He submitted that in the instant case, admittedly, the monthly amount due was not deposited within the time provided and as there was no explanation/ representation to condone the delay, the order striking off defence cannot be faulted and since the court below has passed the judgment and decree after considering the plaintiff's evidence, which was tested by cross-examination, the finding returned by the court below on various issues which is based on appreciation of evidence and is not perverse, cannot be interfered with in exercise of revisional powers.
Court below in specific terms has held that from the evidence on record in the present case and in view of the above noticed legal position, it is amply proved that the accused intentionally aimed and inflicted the injury with the deadly weapon i.e. the (Kirch) and this injury was sufficient in the ordinary course of nature to cause the death of the deceased.
P.C. thereafter the learned court below has got no jurisdiction to exercise the power under or (NnUuMm३)  ., by which, FIR could have been registered and as such, the order dated NnUuMm१.NnUuMm२.NnUuMm० passed by the learned Court below is illegal and without jurisdiction.

P.NnUuMm०, becomes dying declaration and the oral evidence of
P.W.NnUuMm१ before the Court remain totally unchallenged during the course of trial before the court below.
It is further urged that at best, Court below could have imposed cost on the appellants for the inconvenience caused to the other side.
The findings so recorded by the Court below are the findings of fact based on consideration of relevant evidences on record and, therefore, it cannot be interfered with in the present Revisions filed by the revisionists defendants under of Provincial Small Cause Courts Act, NnUuMm०.
On the basis of the above broad allegations the court below had framed charges against the accused, to which they had pleaded not guilty and claimed to be tried.
Being aggrieved by the said judgment and order of conviction and the sentence imposed in the case, the appellants/accused have preferred the above appeals challenging the legality and correctness of the judgment and order of the Court below on the grounds as mentioned in the respective appeal memorandum.
Accordingly, the judgment of conviction and order of sentence dated NnUuMm१.0NnUuMm२.NnUuMm० passed by learned court below is set aside and appeal is allowed.
The court below also marked Exts.
The respondent's counsel submits that they are prepared to furnish sufficient bank guarantee of the City Union Bank, Madurai, to the satisfaction of the court below concerned.
It is contended that the conviction by the court below cannot be sustained and prayed that accordingly the same may be set aside.The Court has to take into consideration the mental capacity of the child to recollect what had happened when she was aged about NnUuMm३ or NnUuMm२ years and whether she could (be) able to identify the person who committed the heinous crime on her or is the child in a position to say about the sexual act committed on her, when the child is not aware of such acts, that too when she was in the age group of NnUuMm१ to NnUuMm० years at the time of recording of evidence before the Court below.
File of court below is sent back with direction to court below to decide the case expeditiously as already more than NnUuMm० years has passed from commencement of trial.
We do not find even any process of admission or denial of documents by other side as also process of marking of Exhibit by Court below in regard to such documents.
Admittedly, in this case, the bail bonds furnished by the petitioner, while the petitioner was granted bail by the court below, has not been cancelled, nor the bonds were forfeited.
Court below has held that prosecution has proved its case beyond reasonable doubts.
By conduct both the parties have accepted procedure followed by Court below by treating documents filed and given paper numbers, constituting valid evidence for the purpose of deciding suit.
Besides others, claimant/landowners placed before Court below following documents as exemplar.
She further contended that the Court below has failed to notice para-NnUuMm३ of the plaint wherein it is stated that the plaintiff at Bangalore office scrutinized the application submitted by the defendant and on NnUuMm१.NnUuMm४.NnUuMm० issued a Cancard Visa to the defendant and at para-NnUuMm२ that the Court at Bangalore has jurisdiction to try the suit, but the same has not been considered by the Court below.
Therefore, there is absolutely no reason to interfere with the impugned conviction as well as sentence awarded by the court below.
This argument has been repelled by court below by stating that the place of occurrence is situated inside the area of bus stand
R.S Pura as per the site plan EXPW-VP and is surrounded by shops on all the sides with a passage for incoming and outgoing vehicles from the but stand area.
It is the illegality committed and also misreading the evidence, committed by the Court below in coming to such conclusion.
Learned senior counsel further submits that the entire conviction hinges on the evidence of the alleged sole eyewitness, i.e. PWNnUuMm० and the evidence of PWNnUuMm१, being not reliable, should have been discarded by the Court below and the appellants should have been released.
Mr.
B.T.
Shukla) was placed on record of learned Labour Court below list of document dated NnUuMm२.NnUuMm१.NnUuMm०.
The Court below itself examined, compared the documents and recorded a satisfaction with regard to signature of the plaintiff Santosh.
Court below has thus rightly repelled the argument of prosecution by cogent manner in treating the initial statement of deceased as dying declaration.
On appreciation of the oral and documentary evidence, the Court below, while acquitting accused Nos.NnUuMm२ and NnUuMm१ of all the offences punishable under Section-NnUuMm० read with
I.P.C. and read with
I.P.C., however, convicted accused No.NnUuMm३ for the offence punishable under
I.P.C. It is not understood why learned Court below not insisted upon defendant to place on record plan sanctioned by it while granting permission to plaintiff for fixing rolling shutter on the tenanted premises.
So finding of Court below with this regard is neither perverse nor against the law.
I have considered the contents of petition and record of court below.
After having carefully perused the impugned judgment of acquittal viz-a-viz evidence adduced on record by the prosecution, this Court is not persuaded to agree with the contention having been made by learned Additional Advocate General, that learned court below has not read the evidence in its right perspective, as a result of which, erroneous findings have come on record.
The following documentary evidence was taken into consideration by the learned Court below.
However, the jail sentence imposed by the court below will stand reduced to rigorous imprisonment for one year.
RPC was established, so investigation was culminated in the charge sheet before court below.
There is no denying the fact that if the said sample was not found to contain heroin, the court below would have no option but to pass an acquittal order.
In order to facilitate an expeditious trial of the suit, we direct the parties to be present through their respective counsel before the court below on NnUuMm१.NnUuMm२.NnUuMm०, on which day, the court below shall afford an opportunity for filing a written statement to the appellant.This Notary has been examined by the court below as DWNnUuMm०.
There are inconsistencies in the statements of prosecution witnesses with regard to time, place and presence of the witnesses on the spot and even the sole independent witness associated by the prosecution has turned hostile and he has nowhere supported the prosecution case, as such, there is no illegality or infirmity in the judgment of acquittal recorded by the learned Court below, which is definitely based upon proper appreciation of evidence.
A copy of this judgment be sent to the Court below for information and compliance.
Thus, by taking this Court through the relevant evidence on record, the learned Additional Public Prosecutor submitted that the findings recorded by the learned Court below are based on oral as well as documentary evidence.
The petitioners refer to
I.A No.NnUuMm० of NnUuMm१ filed by one of them in the court below.
In present case, it is not a case that court below was not having jurisdiction to grant the bail.
There is no prohibition to entertain a second appeal even on question of fact, provided the Court is satisfied that the findings of the courts below were vitiated by non-consideration of relevant evidence or by showing erroneous approach to the matter and findings recorded in the court below are perverse.Let a copy of order be sent to the court below and also handed over to learned APP for transmission to the
I.O.
and also sent to the concerned Bank through 'FAX'.No material contradiction was found by the learned court below in the statements of the witnesses of fact and ultimately finding the case proved against the accused beyond reasonable doubt, it awarded punishment to the appellant mentioned above.
After hearing the parties the Court below has convicted and sentenced the accused/appellant as mentioned above in paragraph No.NnUuMm० of this judgment.
The conviction and sentence against him in
S.C NnUuMm१/NnUuMm० of the court below will stand set aside.
In our view, the Court below has rendered a finding without properly appreciating the oral and the documentary evidence filed on the side of the parties.
Appellant court has held that court below has categorically recorded his awareness in appreciating the statement of victim who was minor child and thereafter held that there was sufficient corroboration from other statements.
The Appellate Court is not permitted to re-assess the material and seek to reach a conclusion different from the one reached by the Court below, if the discretion has been expressed by the Trial Court reasonably and in a judicial manner.
Therefore, after close scrutiny of the case, I am of the opinion that the prosecution has been able to prove the case and the learned court below has not erred in giving the finding of dowry death.
Needless to say, the appellant will be entitled to apply for restitution of her property, which has been sold by the court below in execution of the decree that we have already set aside in this appeal and we leave the appellant to pursue the appropriate remedies for this purpose under the provisions of the Code of Civil Procedure.
High Court cannot examine the evidence as to whether the offences for which cognizance are taken by court below is made out or not.
Soma Thakur, Advocate, that Court below has erred in not discussing the entire oral as well as documentary evidence while reversing the findings returned by learned trial Court.
The court below has examined this aspect of the matter.

S.P.
Renukaji for investigation and as such, learned court below has rightly concluded that averments contained in the FIR are second thought and as such, cannot be relied upon.
The court below has thus rightly decreed the suit for the rate of interest at NnUuMm१/NnUuMm०% per annum.
This being the position, we are of the considered view that the impugned order passed by the Court below dismissing the suit on the point of maintainability, without deciding source of the suit property, is absolutely illegal and cannot be sustained in the eyes of law.
The learned lower Appellate Court set aside the findings returned by the learned trial Court below.
The summary of the case of the claimants in the Court below is that, on 0NnUuMm१.0NnUuMm२.NnUuMm० Sri.

M.F.A. Nos.NnUuMm६, NnUuMm५, NnUuMm४, NnUuMm३, NnUuMm२, NnUuMm१ and NnUuMm० OF NnUuMm७ claimants were not stipulated under (NnUuMm८) of the and the Court below should have held that, they can never constitute as a provision enabling the land owners seeking for enhancement of the compensation as determined by the Arbitrator.
As already held, I do not find any infirmity of law and facts in the finding of the Court below while awarding the compensation, hence this appeal is dismissed.
Further, considering that the execution proceeding involving the parties is pending since NnUuMm१, this Court directs the judgment debtor to file its objection on the date of appearance in the Court below on NnUuMm२th of October, NnUuMm० alongwith payment of cost also on the same date.
Lastly the court below held that it was well proved by the prosecution that the recovered contraband material was weighed on the spot and its sample, which was sent to the
F.S.L., was found to contain charas which proved beyond doubt that the accused was found in illegal possession of NnUuMm१.NnUuMm० kg. The present appellant, who is plaintiff before the Court below, had filed a suit against the defendant in
S.C.No.NnUuMm४/NnUuMm३ for recovery of money contending that the defendant had availed membership of Cancard Visa under the plaintiff's Cancard Scheme, on the basis of which, it had issued Cancard Visa bearing No.NnUuMm२- NnUuMm१-00NnUuMm०.
The charge sheet in question and order of taking cognizance by the Court below is contrary to the documents, Court order and the same is abuse of the process of law and liable to be quashed.
The court below considering the evidence on record in the proper perspective and on the basis of such appreciation of the evidence and pleadings of the parties have come to the concurrent findings and under such circumstances, the first appellate court cannot be held that it upheld the decree of the trial court without considering the merits of the counter claim.
This court has only supervisory power under Section NnUuMm० of CPC and can be exercised only in exceptional cases where the court below failed to exercise jurisdiction vested on it or acted illegally or with material irregularity in exercise of such jurisdiction.
Considering the facts and circumstances of the case, we are of the considered opinion that the view taken by the Court below while convicting the appellants is wrong and the findings recorded by the Court below are perverse, erroneous and can not stand the scrutiny of law.
The third reasoning given by the Court below for acquittal is the alleged suspicion in the recovery of weapons, only because panchas to the seizure panchanama having turned hostile to the prosecution.
The submission of the petitioner in the court below was that this was the essential circumstance, which required a thorough probe and would have provided an evidence for murder.
In 'Part A' of the Appraisal Form, the petitioner had himself filled the requisite informations concerning the work assigned to him which, according to the learned court below had amply demonstrated that the work assigned to the petitioner was of supervisory nature.
This fact has been overlooked by learned court below and the court below has only relied on the statements recorded under of the Cr.
Court below while relying on  .
As has been observed above by the Hon'ble Apex Court that words 'essential to the just decision of the case' are the key words and in this regard Court below, while  . The single point that arises for my consideration is:
Whether the relief of specific performance can be grated to the appellant and whether the judgment of the court below needs any interference.
Based on the charge sheet, the Court below framed the following charges:
The court below, only by applying (NnUuMm०)
(v) of the SC & , the life sentence was awarded.
However, in the present petition, the question for consideration is:
whether the court below has rightly rejected the application of plaintiffs- petitioners herein seeking to place on record the site plans prepared by Architect Suresh Puri.
Therefore, we are of the clear opinion that the Court below has erred in allowing the Application under of the Act of the land-owners and the present appeal of the National Highways Authority deserves to be allowed.
Court below has also held that PW-NnUuMm० (Balwant Singh) has stated that the accused, namely Kuldeep Raj, Shanti Devi (injured) and her son are known to him.
However in the facts what this Court feels to interfere with is only to reduce from Rs.NnUuMm०,NnUuMm२NnUuMm३0/- to Rs.NnUuMm१,000/- per month by otherwise confirming the order of the Court below.On the basis of the evidence on record, the accused persons were convicted and sentenced by the Trial Court below as aforesaid.
Therefore the view of the court below that no representation was made for condoning the delay in making deposit of admitted monthly rent the defence was liable to be struck off, is unsustainable.
Upon hearing, respondent may object to decree as if he had preferred separate appeal.- (NnUuMm०) Any respondent, though he may not have appealed from any part of the decree, may not only support the decree [but may also state that the finding against him in the court below in respect of any issue ought to have been In his favour;
and may also take any cross objection] to the decree which he could have taken by way of appeal, provided he has filed such objection in the Appellate Court within one month from the date of service on him or his pleader of notice of the day fixed for hearing the appeal, or within such further time as the Appellate Court may see fit to allow.
Before coming to the sentence part of this case, to first ensure the compliance on the part of the accused- respondents, we direct the Executing Court below of Fifth Additional Civil Judge and JMFC, Belagavi, who is dealing with the Execution Case No.NnUuMm१ of NnUuMm०, Shri.
